Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 114-166.)
  - On Julius Epstein
    - Wall Street Journal editorial of November 24, 1972
    - Washington Post, 2 folders)
    - Weekly Crusader, January 10, 1969
  - "Operation Eastwind", 5 folders)
  - "Operation Keelhaul." Includes photographs, 3 folders)
  - Opium (from China & South East Asia)
  - Oppenheimer, Fritz E. (obituary)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert J. (on Einstein)
  - Optical illusions
  - Osten, Der aktuelle
  - Oswald, Lee Harvey (Box 137)
    - Clippings
    - Kihss articles
    - Revue series
    - Smith's story
    - Warren Report
    - Washington Report
  - Otepka, Otto F.
  - "Otschen Choroscho"
  - "Our Own Revolution, The Dirt on"
  - Outstanding Educators of America
  - Overclassification
  - Own articles (J. E.)
    - "Ein Amerikanischer Truppenabzug aus Europa?" (withdrawl of American troops from Europe?)
    - Bonn repatriates Hungarian refugees
    - Captive Nations Week
    - Churchill's relation to Roosevelt and Truman
    - "Cold War, The Beginning of", 2 folders)
    - Czechoslovakia (Box 138)
    - Davis, Angela, 2 folders)
    - Donitz, Karl
    - Dubcek, Alexander, 7 folders)
    - Edelsheim, Freiherr von
    - "Did England Consider a Negotiated Peace?"
    - Epstein vs. Resor, Secretary of the Army, 13 folders)
    - Executive Order 11652, 3 folders)
    - Forced repatriation, 6 folders) (Box 139)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 4 folders)
    - "Geheimnisverrates, Zur Problematik des" (the question of secrets-disclosure)
    - Germany-U.S. discord
    - Hammarskjold's death
    - Hess, Rudolf, 14 folders)
    - House Resolution 399
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.
    - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940, 10 folders) (Box 140)
    - Kennedy, John F.
      - General
      - Rapacki Plan, 4 folders)
    - Korea
    - Kosygin (on East Pakistan refugees)
    - Kurile Islands, 4 folders)
    - Lenin, 3 folders)
    - Mao Tse-tung, drug pusher, 5 folders)
    - Masaryk, Thomas, 3 folders)
    - Meir, Golda (on Katyn)
    - Moczar, General
    - Neruda, Pablo
    - Nossenko, Yuri and 'Goloniewski'
    - Nuclear threat
    - Operation Keelhaul, 23 folders) (Box 141)
    - "Otepka, Will Nixon Help?" (Box 142)
    - Pacifism and communism
    - Psychiatrists, 3 folders)
    - Refugees Convention, 4 folders)
    - Re-Stalinization, 3 folders)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. and the extermination of Jews, 4 folders)
    - Rostow, Walt W., 2 folders)
    - Runciman, Lord
    - Schlamm, William S.
    - Shockley, William
    - Soviet cosmonauts and space failures, 11 folders)
    - Stalin (Box 143)
      - Aid to Hitler
      - Treaties that he broke
    - Steenberg, Sven (his book on Vlasov), 3 folders)
    - Svoboda's mission, 1945-1968, 2 folders)
    - UNESCO-Lenin, 3 folders)
    - United Nations Charter violation
    - Vietcong atrocities
    - Vietnam, 8 folders)
    - Vlasov, Andrei A., 2 folders)
    - Yugoslav refugees
  - Own letters to the editor (J. E.), 2 folders)
  - Own photographs (J. E.) (Box 144)
  - Own testimony (J. E.)
    - Katyn, 1952
    - Operation Keelhaul, 1971
  - Paine, T. O., Dr.
    - NASA
    - Questions to
  - Pakistan, East (Bangladesh)
  - Palestine (Arab side)
  - Palmiry, Poland
  - Palo Alto, Stanford Hospital, 1967
  - Palo Alto Times (list of J. E.'s contributions)
  - Panama
    - Canal
    - Drug traffic
  - Panther, Black (split)
  - Papandreou, George
  - Papern, Franz von (obituary)
  - 'Paradise' advocate (for Vietnam)
  - Parry, Albert (on Lenin)
  - Pascal, Blaise
  - Passos, John Dos (obituary)
  - Paul VI (UN speech)
  - Peace Corps
  - Pearl Harbor
    - General
    - Investigation
  - Pearson, Drew
    - General, 4 folders)
    - Obituaries
  - Pegler, Westbrook (obituary)
  - Peking
    - Declaration (lin Piao)
    - "Not Peiping"
  - Penkovsky, Oleg V.
  - Pentagon
    - General
    - Papers
  - Per capita income
  - Perls, Frederick, Dr.
    - General
    - Obituary
  - Persepolis celebration
  - Personalities of the West and Midwest
  - Peter and Pat (photographs of J. E.'s son and his bride)
  - Philathea College (Box 145)
  - Philby, H. A. R.
    - General
    - Interview with Izvestia
  - 'Phone first-aid'
  - Piao, Lin
  - Picasso, Pablo
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Obituary
  - Pike, James A.
  - Pilsen (Czechoslovakia), 1945
  - Pirate radio stations
  - Pius XII
    - Accused of pro-nazism
    - Anti-nazi plot
    - Warning of Nazi invasion
  - Plagiarism
  - Plaza Hotel
  - Poland, Germany, Russia and Austria in history
  - Polish-German Treaty, November 20, 1970
  - Polish Note on forced repatriation
  - Polish-Soviet Treaty, 1970. See Soviet-Polish Treaty, 1970
  - "Political Masterplan of the Future"
  - Politzer, Heinz
  - Polonia Restituta (negative)
  - Popov, Milorad I.
  - Population
    - Explosion (Latin America)
    - And food
  - Pospelov, Pjotr
  - Pospielovsky, Dimitri, 2 folders)
  - Possev News and Feature Service
  - Possony, Stefan
    - "Freedom of Information"
    - Work done by J. E. for, 3 folders)
  - Potsdam, 1945-1970
  - Powell, Adam Clayton
  - Powers, Gary
  - Praxis
  - Predictions
  - Presidency (Life, special issue)
  - Presidential papers
  - Press conferences of J. E. (Box 146)
    - January 10, 1973
      - Announcement
      - Press kit
    - March 21, 1973
  - Private sector in Soviet economy
  - Proofreading (Joseph Lasker)
  - Propaganda
  - "Protest alter Bolschewiki" (Protest from old Bolsheviks)
  - Prytz, Bjorn
  - PSA instant tickets
  - Psychiatry, 2 folders)
  - Psychoanalysis, Doom of (Jean Piaget)
  - Public Law 648
  - Pueblo ship
  - Puerto Rico
  - Pursuit satellites
  - Quaison-Sackey, Alex (Box 147)
  - Quotations
  - Racconigi Treaty
  - Radio Free Europe, 2 folders)
  - Radvanyi, Janos, 2 folders)
  - Ranki, Gyorgy
  - Rapacki, Adam (at UN General Assembly)
  - Rarick, John A. (on Operation Keelhaul), 2 folders)
  - Rechberg, Arnold
    - General
    - Affidavit
    - Articles
    - Kernbach correspondence
    - Memoirs
  - Red block disunity
  - Red China
    - Lobby
    - In the United Nations, November 1970
  - Red Cross (blames U.S. and Saigon for prisoners)
  - Refugees
    - In Austria
    - Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees
  - Reid, Ogden, Mrs. (obituary)
  - Reik, Theodore, Dr. (obituary)
  - Release of information (Army regulation, 1967)
  - Rendulic. Lothar von
  - Renegades and Quislings directive
  - Repatriation
    - Arrangements, U.S.-U.S.S.R., 1944
    - Of Koreans in Japan
  - Republican Platform
    - 1964
    - 1968
    - 1972
  - Reston, James (Box 148)
    - "A View from Peking"
    - Interview with Chou En-lai
  - Resuscitation in England
  - Reuther, Walter
  - Revisionist books (bibliography)
  - Rheinischer Merkur (on Peking's arsenal)
  - Rhodesia, 2 folders)
  - Ribbentrop, Joachim von
  - Riot report
  - Rohe, Mies van der (obituary)
  - Romania
    - General
    - Backs Red China
    - Vs. Moscow
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
    - And Churchill during World War II
    - In India
    - And Stalin
      - General
      - Recognizes Stalin's true policy in 1945
  - Roosevelt, Kermit (on Palestine)
  - Ropke, Wilhelm
  - Rosenthal, Leo (obituary)
  - Rostow, Walter W.
    - Interview
    - Leeds speech
  - Rote Kapelle
  - Rothbard, Murray N.
  - Rothermere, Lord
  - Rubin, Berthold
  - Rubin, Jerry
  - Runge, Yevgeny Y., 2 folders)
  - Rush, Myron
  - Rusk, Dean
  - Russell, Bertrand, Lord
    - War Crime Trial
    - Obituary
  - Russia. See Poland
  - Sachs, Nelly (Box 149)
  - Sakharov, Andrei D., 2 folders)
  - Salazar, Antonio (obituary)
  - Salote, Queen of Tonga (obituary)
  - "Samisdat," Russian-American
  - Samizdat
    - General
    - Bulletin
  - San Francisco Chronicle (anniversary edition)
  - Saragat, Giuseppe
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul
  - Satellite forbidden
  - Savinkov, Boris
    - General
    - Trial
  - Scaife, Alan, Mrs. (obituary)
  - Scanlan's
  - Schaff, Adam (on Marx)
  - Schapiro, L. B.
  - Schirach, Baldur von
  - Schlamm, William S.
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr.
  - Schlink, Basilea, Mother
  - Schnabel, Arthur
  - Schonberg, Hans W.
  - Schops, Hans-Joachim
  - Schuschnigg, Kurt von
  - Schwartz, Abba P.
  - Schwartz, Harry
  - Schwebel, Stephen M., 2 folders)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, Dr.
    - Life story, 1965
    - Obituary
  - Schwelb, Egon, 2 folders)
  - Scott-Allen Report (reveals death of 11 cosmonauts from the U.S.S.R.) (Box 150)
  - S.D.S. (Students for a Democratic Society)
  - Seale, Bobby (trial)
  - SEATO
  - Second trial (J. E. et al. vs. Robert F. Frohlke, Secretary of the Army)
    - Complaint
    - Army's answer
  - Security Council of the United Nations (voting procedure)
  - Seger, Gerhart (obituary)
  - Selence material
  - Selma, Alabama
  - Serbsky 'Institute'
  - Servan-Schreiber, Jean-Jacques
  - Seventy-seven word murder trial
  - "Shape of the Future"
  - Shapiro, Leonard, 5 folders)
  - Sharp, Grant, Admiral
  - Shawcross, Hartley, Sir
  - Shearer, Lloyd (insertion on classification) (Box 151)
  - Sheen, Fulton, Bishop
  - Shockley, M.
  - Shoplifting
  - Shub, David (obituary)
  - Sign language
  - Sikorski, General
    - General
    - Hochhuth, Rolf
  - Sikorsky, Igor (obituary)
  - "Silesia Is a German Region"
  - Silent sound ('acoustic' laser)
  - "Sino-Soviet Relationship and the United States" (Harry G. Gelber)
  - Sinyavsky, Andrei D.
    - General, 2 folders)
    - And Yuli M. Daniel
  - Skyjackers
  - Smith, Edward Ellis
    - Letter to the Palo Alto Times
    - Penkovskiy series
  - Smith, Frederic N. (notes to his dissertation)
  - Snapshots (taken by J. E.)
  - Snow, Edgar (obituary)
  - Sobolev, Arkady A. (obituary)
  - Social sciences, 1969
  - Social Security
    - General
    - Increase, 1972
  - Solar furnace
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr I.
    - General, 2 folders)
    - "August 1914"
    - Nobel Prize
      - General
      - Acceptance speech
  - Sonnino, Sidney, Baron
  - Sorensen, Theodore C. (on Kennedy)
  - Sorokin, Pitirim A.
  - Source material, 2 folders)
  - South Africa
    - General
    - Verwoerd's murder (Box 152)
    - Vorster's regime
  - South Vietnam atrocities
  - South West Africa (UN decision)
  - Soviet accusations of Israel and West Germany producing nuclear weapons in the Negev desert
  - Soviet-American summit meeting, Moscow, May 1972
  - Soviet annexations (Emery Reves)
  - Soviet anti-semitism
  - Soviet celebration of the 50th anniversary of the revolution
  - Soviet Communist Party (24th Congress, 1971)
  - Soviet complaints
    - About poor workmanship in plants
    - Against Eisenhower
  - Soviet consumer situation
  - Soviet deceptions, 2 folders)
  - Soviet farm production
  - Soviet-German Treaty, August 11, 1970
  - Soviet incentive wages
  - Soviet Information Bulletin (Soviet Embassy, Washington, D.C.) (Box 153)
    - 1942
    - 1943, 2 folders)
    - 1944
    - 1944 (Box 154)
    - 1945
    - 1946, 2 folders)
    - 1947
    - 1948
  - Soviet intellectuals and others appeal... (Box 155)
  - Soviet invasion of Czechoslovakia, 1968
  - Soviet links to Norway
  - Soviet party history revised
  - Soviet-Polish Treaty, 1970
  - Soviet prison brutality, 1969
  - Soviet productivity
  - Soviet protests to Czechoslovakia
  - Soviet record (Young Americans for Freedom)
  - Soviet slave labor camps, 1967
  - Soviet space failures, 7 folders)
  - Soviet space failures (Box 156)
  - Soviet space missiles
  - Soviet space program
    - "Review of the Soviet Space Program," 1967
    - Ten years in space
  - Soviet 'space walk' hoax
  - Soviet 'special psychiatric hospitals', 2 folders)
  - Soviet Venus shot
  - Soviet violation of international postal regulations
  - Soviet writers
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Congress, 1967
  - Space Treaty (United Nations), 4 folders)
  - Spaniel, A. N., 2 folders)
  - Speed reading
  - Spellman, Cardinal
  - Spiegel, August 4, 1965 (on J. E.)
  - Springer, Axel
    - General
    - Stern story
  - The SS and July 20, 1944 (Box 157)
  - Staar, Richard F.
  - Stalin, Joseph
    - 90th anniversary of birth
    - 20th anniversary of death
    - Execution of 25 Jewish intellectuals
    - Exoneration of his mass deportations
    - Reunification offered to West Germany in exchange of staying out of Western alliance
  - Stalin, Svetlana, 2 folders)
  - Stalin, Yakov
  - Stanford salary data
  - State Department (Bulletin)
  - State Department (Bulletin) (Box 158)
  - Stedry, Vladimir (Box 159)
  - Stern documents
  - Stettinius on Prague
  - Stevenson, Adlai E.
    - Congo speech, December 14, 1964
    - Life story
  - Stieff, H., General Major
  - Strauss, Franz Joseph, Dr., 2 folders)
  - Strausz-Hupe, Robert
  - Studnicki, Wladyslaw
  - Subversion
  - Suez Canal
  - Suicide
    - General
    - Of psychiatrists
  - Sukarno
  - Sukiennicki, Wiktor
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays (obituary)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs (on Vietnam Papers)
  - Sulzberger, Cyrus L., 3 folders)
  - Sunday Times, January 2, 1966 (the Adenauer affair)
  - Super rich Americans
  - "Supreme Command" (Forrest C. Pogue)
  - Svatos, Ladislav
  - Sworakowski, Witold S.
  - Szasz, Thomas
  - Szent-Gyorgi, Albert
  - Tactics
  - Taiwan, 3 folders)
  - Tapley, Christine (on J. E.'s manuscript, "Forced Repatriation")
  - Taracouzio, T. A.
  - Tate, Sharon (murder case)
  - Taxes
    - 1965
    - 1966
    - 1967
    - 1970
    - 1971
    - House Bill, 1969
  - Taylor, A. J. P. (Box 160)
  - Taylor, Telford
  - Teapot Dome scandal
  - Teheran and Yalta
  - Teller, Edward
  - Temple Scroll
  - "Teutonenschwert" (German sword)
  - Thayer, Charles W. (on Germany, 1967)
  - Thomas, J. Parnell (obituary)
  - Thomas, Norman (obituary)
  - Thompson, Llewellyn (Ambassador-at-Large, on Austria)
  - Thompson, Robert Glenn (spy for Soviets)
  - Thurmond, Strom
  - Times, London, 2 folders)
  - Tito
    - General
    - Sulzberger interview
  - Togliatti, Palmiro (memorandum)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra, Countess
  - Tonga (independence)
  - Tonkin Resolution
  - Toynbee's predictions
  - Trade with communist bloc
  - Trevor-Roper, Hugh (on China and Taiwan)
  - Trotsky, Leon, 2 folders)
  - True magazine (on death of Soviet cosmonauts)
  - Truman, Harry S
    - Against forced repatriation
    - Doctrine
    - Obituary
    - "Verlangerte Truman den Krieg?" (did Truman prolong the war?)
  - Twain, Mark
  - Twenty-third Congress of the Communist Party of the U.S.S.R.
  - Typesetting
  - Typing instructions
  - Ukrainian 'trials' in 1965-1966 (Box 161)
  - Ulbricht, Walter
  - Ullrich, Johannes, Dr., 3 folders)
  - United Nations Organization
    - 1969-1970
    - Charter
    - And China
      - Debate, October 1971
      - "United Nations Membership for Mao?"
      - Voting procedure
    - Convention on Refugees, 2 folders)
    - Declaration on Territorial Asylum
    - Declaration on Women's Rights
    - Economic and Social Council, 1946, 3rd session
    - General Assembly, 1947
    - High Commissioner for Refugees (statute of office)
    - Human Rights
      - General
      - Complaints
    - And Korea, 2 folders)
    - Non-Self-Governing Territories, 2 folders) (Box 162)
    - Relief and Rehabilitation Administration
    - Report of the Secretary General, 1946
    - Roster, 1960
    - Structure, 1967-1968
    - Telephone directories, 1946
    - Terms of the League of Nations Mandates
    - Total payments to, 1970
    - Weekly Bulletin, October 21, 1946
  - United States of America
    - Congress (Standing Committees of the House)
    - And Czechoslovakia
    - Drug scene (New York Times)
    - Information Agency
    - Leaflets
    - And Prussia (treaties of 1785, 1799, and 1828)
    - Resolution and Draft Convention on Terrorism
    - And the Soviet Union
      - Brezhnev Doctrine
      - Draft convention on bacteriological arms
      - Pacts on averting atom war and on hot line
      - Rapprochement
      - Treaty on fishing off Alaska
    - And Taiwan (Mutual Defense Treaty, December 2, 1954)
  - Urban, Rudolf, Dr.
  - U.S.S.R. (ouster from the League of Nations)
  - Vardikos, Nicolas
  - Varga, Eugene (obituary)
  - Vatican II (Box 163)
    - Abolition of secret trials
    - Bishops' 'revolt'
    - And Jews, 3 folders)
    - And the Kremlin
    - And Orthodox
    - Sainthood for priests
    - Sessions
      - 1964, 2 folders)
      - 1965, 2 folders)
  - Vegetative 'reproduction' of man
  - "Verjahrung fur Nazi-Verbrecher" (prescriptions for Nazi criminals)
  - Verlaine
  - Vichy (surrender treaty)
  - Victims of Bolshevism
  - Vietcong
    - Atrocities
    - Tactics
  - Vietnam. See also Korea
    - Agreement, 1973
    - Chronology, 1940-1973
    - Diplomatic brokers used by the U.S.
    - Fall, Bernard B. (interview)
    - Forced repatriation, 3 folders)
    - General Vo Nguyen Giap
    - Generals against the war
    - Moratorium Day, October 15, 1969
    - National Liberation Front (policy statement)
    - Paris Conference, 1968
    - Reversal
    - 14 Scholars' statement
    - Short history
    - U.S. war crimes
    - White paper
  - Vlasov, General
    - Case (George Fischer)
    - Negatives
  - Voegelin, Eric, Professor, 3 folders) (Box 164)
  - Voice of America
  - Voroshilov, Kliment Y., Marshal (obituary)
  - Voznesensky, Andrei A.
  - Wagner, Richard - Archives
  - Wallenberg, Raoul
  - Walsh, Maurice N.
  - Wankowicz, Melchior
  - War deaths
  - War historical survey
  - War as permanent condition
  - Warranties
  - Warren Report
    - New York Times, 3 folders)
    - Omissions
    - Testimonies
    - In the U.S.S.R.
  - Warsaw (U.S. Embassy budged) (Box 165)
  - Watergate, 2 folders)
  - Wazeter, Francis J. (obituary)
  - 'Weak link' theory (A. N. Lagovskiy)
  - Webb, James E.
  - Wehner, Herbert, 3 folders)
  - Weimar Republic
  - Welch, Robert
  - Wellensky, Roy, Sir
  - Wender, Jur Hans, Dr., 2 folders)
  - Weygand, Maxime, General
  - Weyl, Nathaniel
  - White, William S.
  - "Who Is the Imperialist?", 2 folders)
  - Widener, Alice, 3 folders)
  - Wiesenthal, Simon
  - Wilhelm II (letters to Tsar Nicholas II)
  - Willoughby, Charles, Major General (obituary)
  - Wilson, Woodrow
    - General
    - 14 Points
  - Winchell, Walter
  - Witch doctors
  - Wohl, Paul, Dr.
  - Wolf, Karl Dietrich
  - Wolfe, Bertram D., 4 folders)
  - World archivists
  - World population, 2 folders)
  - World Psychiatrists Congress, Mexico City, 1971
  - World Refugee Report
    - 1970
    - 1971
  - World War I (Box 166)
    - Debt
    - Guilt in
  - World War II ("President Roosevelt and the Coming of the War of 1941")
  - Woytinsky, Emma (obituary)
  - Wraga, Nathalie
  - Wraga, Ryszard
  - Wu, Yuan-li, Dr.
  - Xerox pop art
  - Xeroxes of German documents
  - Yalta. See also Leaders at Yalta; Teheran
    - General
    - Agreement
    - Documents
  - Yergan, Max, Dr.
  - Yevtushenko, Yevgeny ("Who Are You, Grand Canyon?")
  - Youssoupoff, Irina, Princess (obituary)
  - Yugoslavia
    - General
    - "New Economics"
  - Zawodnyk, J. K.
  - Zechlin, Egmont (on Bethmann Hollweg)
  - Zellerbach Report
  - Zhukov (on Stalin)
  - Ziferstein, Isidore
  - Zinoviev Letter
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 167-180.)
  - Acheson, Dean (and Korea) (Box 167)
    - Press conference, October 1952
    - "The Problem of Peace in Korea"
    - Reaction to India's proposal on prisoners of war
    - Speech, October 24, 1952
  - Alliluyeva, Svetlana
  - Appendices
  - Armand, I. F.
  - Armistice: Petain-Hitler
  - Army Quarterly (British)
  - Asylum, Right of (Council of Europe)
  - Austrian State Treaty, 9 folders)
  - Bang-Jensen case (documentation) (Box 168)
  - Baltics' forced repatriation
  - Barmine-Berezov testimony (Box 169)
  - Bessell, Peter
  - Bibliography (general)
  - Bosch Resolution, 3 folders)
  - Bosilievic, Joseph V.
  - Calvocoressi, Peter
  - Carey, Jane Perry Clarck (on displaced populations)
  - Clause, James D. (on deserters)
  - Clippings, 4 folders)
  - Commons, House of (Second World War official histories)
  - Congressional Record (Box 170)
  - Degras, Jane, "Soviet Documents on Foreign Policy"
  - Denikin, A. (letter to Eisenhower)
  - Department of State documents
  - Displaced persons in Germany
  - Documentary annex
  - Documents to be used
  - Epstein, Julius (Box 171)
    - Manuscripts
    - Notes to Dozer's manuscript, "The State Department Won't Tell You"
    - Testimony before Senate Internal Security Subcommittee
    - Statement before Senate Appropriations Committee, 2 folders)
  - Executive Order
    - 10501
    - 10964
    - 11652
  - Fischer, George (on Vlasov)
  - Forced repatriation (bibliography of J. E.)
  - Freedom of Information Act (Box 172)
  - Gaulle, Charles de (on Vlasov)
  - Intelligence, Testing of
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - Clippings
    - Photographs (Box 173)
    - Releases, documents, etc., 5 folders)
  - Le Monde (photostats of various articles)
  - Moor, Carl (Box 174)
  - Moss Act test in trial, 10 folders)
  - Novoye Russkoe Slovo (Box 175)
  - Nuremberg Trial
  - Operation Keelhaul
  - Oswald, Lee Harvey
  - Polish American Journal (various issues) (Box 176)
  - Publications
  - Publications (Box 177)
  - Space (Box 178)
    - America's program
    - Satellite situation report
    - Soviet space failures, 10 folders)
  - Der Tagesspiegel (various issues) (Box 179)
  - West und Ost (various issues) (Box 180)
- INCREMENT, FEBRUARY 1982. (Boxes 181-210.)
  Correspondence, scrapbooks, writings, and printed matter, arranged by physical form
  - Correspondence (Box 181)
    - 1962-1966
    - 1967-1968 (Box 182)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 183)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 184)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 185)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 186)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 187)
  - Writings (Box 188)
    - "American Diplomatic History," 1966
    - "Aus den Dokumenten der Potsdamer Konferenz," n.d.
    - "Aus den Potsdam-Dokumenten," n.d.
    - "Die Frau als Staatsprostituierte," n.d.
    - "Freiherr von Edelsheim: Pace-Maker of German Invasions in England and North America," n.d.
    - Operation Keelhaul: The Story of Forced Repatriation, 1974 - Drafts
    - Operation Keelhaul: The Story of Forced Repatriation, 1974 - Drafts (Box 189)
    - "Soviet Failures in Space," n.d.
    - "Die Verschworung von Teheran," n.d.
    - "Zum amerikanischen Fiasko in Kuba," n.d.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 191)
  - Subject file
    - Berlin
    - Geneva Convention, 1929
    - Geneva Convention, 1949
    - Grew (Joseph C.) note
    - Hague Conventions, 1899 and 1907
    - Hecimovic, Joseph - Bleiburg tragedy
    - Hess, Rudolf
    - Hickerson, John D.
    - Hilldring, Assistant Secretary of State
    - History of the Second World War
    - Human rights
    - Huxley-Blythe, Peter J.
    - Ideas to be dealt with
    - Implementation rules - Yalta
    - International Convention against Forced Repatriation
    - International Rescue Committee
    - Italian Constitution
    - Jackson, Robert H. - Report on war crime trials (Box 192)
    - Joint Chiefs of Staff
    - Kenny, John P.
    - Kerensky, Alexander
    - Kleist, Peter, Dr.
    - Korea
    - Kostring, Ernst, General
    - Kravchenko, Victor A.
    - Lauterpacht, H.
    - Leaflets
    - Library Quarterly
    - McCarran-Walter Act
    - McGinness, John R.
    - Marshall, George C.
    - Military government
    - Morgenstern, Felice
    - Non-applicability of statute of limitations to war crimes and crimes against humanity
    - Nostitz, Siegfried von
    - Possony, Stefan T.
    - Test-ban treaty
  - Miscellany (Box 193-194)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 195)
    - 1943-1949
    - 1949-1953 (Box 196)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 197)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 198)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 199)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 200)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 201)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 202)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 203)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 204)
    - 1963-1967 (Box 205)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 206)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 207)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 208)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 209)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 210)